PETER

REGAN

PIANIST PIANO TEACHER **EVENT CREATOR**



0770 4055 264



regan.peter.w@gmail.com



www.peterreganpiano.com



Peter Regan's career as a pianist has seen him perform in Carnegie Hall New York, the Four Seasons Centre for Performing Arts Toronto, the National Concert Hall Dublin, Stoller Hall Manchester and in venues throughout the UK, Ireland, the USA, Italy, Canada, Spain, Switzerland, Finland, the Netherlands, Poland, Germany and Austria. His Performances have been broadcast on RTÉ Radio One and RTÉ Lyric FM. As an events manager he established and directs Roscommon Chamber Music Festival and Fulham Fest Chamber Music Festival, organised his own nationwide Irish recital tour, has presented several solo recitals in Ireland in aid of charity and presented a multiinstitutional collaborative show involving the Royal Conservatory of Music Toronto, Canada's Ballet Jörgen and University of Toronto while he was student union president at the Glenn Gould School of Music. In addition to his performing activities, Peter is an active piano teacher working with students ranging from four years old to middle age.



Education:

September 2018 – August 2020: M.Mus, Royal College of Music, London.

September 2014 – May 2018: B.Mus and Performance Diploma Programme, Glenn Gould School of Music, Royal Conservatory of Music Toronto, Canada. Graduated as honour roll student on Dean's List. Student union president during 2016/17 academic year.



Event Management Experience:

June 2022: Roscommon Chamber Music Festival, Roscommon Arts Centre and King House Boyle, Ireland. This project consisted of 14 musicians performing 3 concerts over 2 days in 2 different venues.

August 2021: Fulham Fest Chamber Music Festival, St. John's Church, Fulham. This project consisted of 15 musicians performing 3 concerts over 2 days as well as presenting a community outreach workshop.

August 2019: Songs and Dances of Europe, duo recital, Christchurch Cathedral Waterford, Ireland.

July 2019: Fantastique, solo recital, Town Hall Theatre, Galway, Ireland.

March 2018: Solo recital in aid of Peter McVerry Trust, Maynooth University, Ireland.

April 2017: Kinaesthesia, Temerty Theatre, Toronto. This was a multi-disciplinary project involving 18 musicians from the Royal Conservatory of Music Toronto, 15 dancers from Canada's Ballet Jörgen and 3 composers from the University of Toronto.

July - August 2016: Jubilation, solo recital tour across 3 different venues in Ireland. Proceeds were donated to Join Our Boys Trust and Habitat for Humanity.

August 2014: The Last Rose of Summer, charity concert in aid of St. Christopher's Services for the Disabled, Longford, Ireland.

May 2013: Melodies in May, fundraising concert with celebrated pianist John O'Conor. This enabled Peter to travel to and participate in the Aspen Music Festival and School 2013.

Skills Developed:

- Logistics management: Organising Roscommon and Fulham Fest Chamber Music Festivals involved booking the artists, performance venues, recording engineers, accommodation, rehearsal venues and scheduling rehearsal times. It also involved acting as a travel agent and making transport arrangements for the 13 other musicians involved (14 in the case of Fulham Fest). Kinaesthesia involved coordinating the schedules of up to 25 individual musicians and dancers at a given time.
- Public relations and marketing skills: As part of these events Peter coordinated advertising campaigns in national broadcast media, arranged live interviews on national and local radio, wrote editorials for regional press, coordinated print advertising campaigns in regional press, created social media advertising campaigns involving both video editing and graphic design, designed and distributed road sign advertisements,

designed and printed concert programme booklets and built both the www.roscommonchambermusicfestival.com and www.fulhamfest.com websites and e-commerce platforms.

- Fundraising: Both chamber music festival projects involved fundraising significant amounts of money. Peter successfully fundraised €18,800 for Roscommon Chamber Music Festival and £14,600 for Fulham Fest from a mixture of public institutions, private individual donors and corporate sponsors.
- Relationship management: Acquiring sponsors also means ensuring they feel their donation is worthwhile,
 valued and recognised. This means these relationships require significant aftercare post-event in the form of
 personalised thank you gifts, public acknowledgment and the offer of discounted services in future in
 exchange for sponsorship. Relationships between musicians must also be maintained to facilitate smooth
 rehearsals and relationships with subcontractors and public institution leaders must be maintained to ensure
 high quality services during events.
- Administration: Both chamber music festivals required incorporating private limited companies. This is a
 particularly bureaucratic process in Ireland including the design of the company's constitution and
 registering for corporation tax. For Roscommon Chamber Music Festival, Peter is the acting tax agent as well
 as director.
- Budget Management: Directing these festivals involved ascertaining all possible costs, fundraising for costs, accounting for error and unforeseen costs, and responsible dispensation of funds.
- Leadership and Delegation: Peter runs Fulham Fest with two colleagues. He motivates, sets targets for the team and holds monthly accountability meetings to keep on schedule for our goals.
- Presenting, Public Speaking and Performing: All of these events required Peter to act as MC and guide audiences through the shows as well as performing the music in the shows.



Teaching Experience:

January 2015 – Present: Self-employed private piano teacher, Toronto and London.

July 2014 – July 2018: Irish Sailing Association accredited sailing instructor, Lough Ree Yacht Club.

August 2017: Junior fleet race officer, Lough Ree Yacht Club Regatta.



Other Team and Leadership Experience:

August 2018: Sailing instructor and safety officer for "Sounding the Shore" Arts and Heritage Project, Roscommon County Council.

September 2016 – May 2017: Student Union President, Glenn Gould School of Music, Royal Conservatory of Music Toronto.

November 2017 – May 2018: Choir director, Bethany Baptist Church, Toronto.

October 2015 – December 2016: Choir repetiteur, Crestwood School and De La Salle College "Oaklands", Toronto.

Skills Developed:

Teamwork and Leadership: Being SU president involved communicating and assigning tasks to other SU
members when organising social events and concert opportunities for the student body. As SU president,
Peter created a multi-institutional performance opportunity for students, a monthly student forum for
performance practice and encouraged the vocal department representative to set up a collaborative concert
with the keyboard department.

As a sailing instructor, Peter worked as part of a team. Daily meetings were held discussing daily and weekly goals for students, planning the logistics of day trips to other locations on the lake and dividing the manual labour tasks fairly.

As choir director, Peter managed rehearsal times efficiently to ensure there would be new music sung at each service every week. Rehearsals involved giving each vocal section support, direction and advice as appropriate.

Communication and relationship management: Being a piano teacher and sailing instructor requires the
ability to use a variety of communication styles in both one-to-one and group contexts. One must be able to
adjust to individual students to allow them to fulfil their potential. It also involves clear communication with
parents regarding their children's progress and goals. Communication is extremely important as part of a
team of sailing instructors, and as a race officer, to ensure all safety requirements for the children are being
met both on land and water.

• Safety Management: Safety requirements regarding personal floatation devices, boat condition, fuel reserves and storage, and radio communication must be taken care of as a sailing instructor to ensure the safety of the group.



Achievements of Musical Excellence:

Solo and Chamber Music Performances in Prestigious Venues: Carnegie Hall New York, the Four Seasons Centre for Performing Arts Toronto, North York Centre for Performing Arts Toronto, National Concert Hall Dublin, Stoller Hall Manchester, St. James's Piccadilly London, Trinity College Dublin, Maynooth University for President of Ireland Mary McAleese.

Solo and Chamber Music Performances at Prestigious Festivals: Clandeboye Festival, Westport Festival of Chamber Music, West Wicklow Festival, Boyle Arts Festival, Kaunas Piano Fest, Royal College of Music Keyboard Festival, Grafenegg Schlosshof.

Concerto Soloist with Orchestra Performances: Mozart Piano Concerto No. 23 with Camerata Ireland and Barry Douglas OBE, Prokofiev Piano Concerto No. 3 with Hibernian Orchestra, Rachmaninoff Piano Concerto No. 2 with Dublin Orchestral Players, Grieg Piano Concerto with Artematica Orchestra.

Orchestral Keyboard Performances: Keyboard player for European Union Youth Orchestra Spring and Summer Tours 2022.

National Prizes: Winner of all major national prizes and bursaries at Electric Ireland Feis Ceoil, Lucien and Maura Teissier Bursary for Piano from Royal Irish Academy of Music, Audrey Chisholm Bursary from Birr Festival of Music.

International Semi-finalist Recognition: Semi-finalist in Branceleoni, Royal Overseas League and Walled City Music Festival international piano competitions. Shortlisted finalist for BBC Symphony Orchestra Pathway Scheme.

Other Performances: Solo and chamber music performances throughout the UK, Ireland, USA, Canada, Italy, Austria, Finland, Switzerland and Spain.

Broadcast: Peter has performed live on RTÉ Radio One (Irish national broadcaster) and has been recorded for RTÉ Lyric FM.

Reviews:

"Peter's playing ... is a joy – the full push of the emotion and tragic drama of the star-crossed lovers Tristan and Isolde hanging in the Christchurch ether." - Pat McEvoy, Waterford News and Star, 13/08/2019

"Regan's interpretation was assertive, large-scale, and tonally powerful, emphasizing the music's tragic character. He weighted the inner voices so that their interplay could be readily heard, and exploited the Steinway Concert Grand's deep, resonant bass register. The audience listened in hypnotic, rapt silence." – Michael Sherwin, The Epoch Times, 17/10/2015

"They also liked Ireland's Peter Regan, in Schoenberg, Debussy and Liszt. Still only 19, he is the most individual and developed young Irish pianist I've heard in years." - Michael Dervan, Irish Times, 20/05/2015

"Regan sounds like a major talent. He completed his Leaving Cert this year but plays with real musical maturity and an easy command. The highlight of the programme were the Six Little Pieces by Arnold Schoenberg, dissonant miniatures from 1911 which Regan delivered with sensuality and an entirely apt romantic sensibility ... Regan also offered the first movement of Schumann's Fantasy in C, Op 17, and the 1931 version of Rachmaninov's Second Piano Sonata. Both are challenges, and he showed he has the technique to shape the bigger picture of both works while keeping control of small details." - Michael Dervan, Irish Times, 10/09/2014

https://vivirjaen.com/un-concierto-memorable/ (for online viewing only), August 2019

References: Available upon request.